NLP engineer

- email: bavadim@gmail.com
- web-site: bavadim.me
- github: github.com/bavadim

Summary

I am an experienced engineer with 10 years of experience. I have created several large projects from scratch. I will be glad to help you if you need a rapid prototype of an Al-based web service, to solve a practical natural language processing task or to set up a machine learning pipeline. Summary of my experience:

- 10 years of industry experience in backend developing distributed applications and high load systems on Scala and Java.
- 3 years of experience in building NLP software: chatbots, model tuning, building ml infrastructure.
- 2 years of managing own company.

Core skills

Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Scala, Akka, pandas, Apache Spark, Chatbot Development, Statistics.

Projects

I have developed several projects from scratch, including projects for large companies such as Sberbank, Russian Railways, Rospechat. For example, this one: http://smartnalog.ru. This is a knowledge base on Russian tax law, developed by me from scratch in 3 months. The main challenge of the project was the development of a search engine. This search engine uses AI technologies (USE, ODQA) to select an article from text knowledge base. The question is forwarded to the lawyer if no article is found. Technological stack: python, typescript, tensorflow.

Another projects you can find on my github.

Publications

date	source	article name
2017	The NIPS '17 Competition: Building Intelligent Systems	Competition on Automatic Evaluation of Dialogue Quality
2018	Radio Metrix	Machine learning in law

Professional experience

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2020 - 2021	Sberbank	TechLead	I was engaged in development of ML components and business analysis for bank skills of the Salut virtual assistant. I have organized an analytic pipeline (which includes stages with manual work, ~20 people engaged in a process) for monitoring users' statisfaction and detecting product problems. Apart from this, I was enganged in a process of support and continuous quality improvment of ML components of the Salut assistant.
2018 - 2020	fastlaw.io	СТО	I am the founder of fastlaw.io. My company offers consulting services and we are creating NLP-based products for EDI automation.
2017 - 2020	DeepPavlov	chief engineer	We were developing an open-source framework for building chatbots. Our framework includes state-of-the-art NLP models. I led the department of business solutions. In this position, I was responsible for analytics and the technical implementation of user products.
2015 - 2017	Raiffeisen Bank	senior developer	I was a developer engaged in the development of mission-critical services of Raiffeisen business online platform: authorization, monitoring, and data storage. We used Scala, Akka, Play framework. In this position, I got experience with SQRS, CRDT and Event sourcing patterns.
2012 - 2015	Edisoft Development Itd.	system architect	Head of the R&D department. I have prototyped several products, e.g. AlfaFactoring platform (high-load project for AlphaBank). In this position, I was leading a team with 6 developers. We used many technologies, but our main stack was Scala, Java and Ruby-based.

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2011 — 2012	Acronis ltd.	software engineer	Participated in the development of Acronis Backup and Recovery for Linux as a developer. In that position, I worked with POSIX API, C++ and Assembler. Moreover, I was a release manager and manage codebase of the Acronis Backup and Recovery project (~90GB in SVN repo). This experience helped me to understand the most important principles of software development.
2008 - 2010	Moscow Power Engineering Institute	developer	Participated in the development software for the Russian Ministry of Education. I was developer of desktop applications. Technological stack based on Java and C#.

Education

year of graduation	school	degree
2010	Moscow Power Engineering Institute (Technical University)	Masters Degree in Computer Science
2011	udacity.com	Artificial Intelligence
2012	Coursera.org	Software Engineering for SaaS
2013	udacity.com	Artificial Intelligence for Robotics
2014	Coursera.org	Machine Learning
2014	Coursera.org	Functional Programming Principles in Scala
2017	HSE University	Masters Degree in Artificial Intelligence